<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on YSMILES HOME</title>
    <link>/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on YSMILES HOME</description>
    <image>
      <title>YSMILES HOME</title>
      <url>%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HTTP server inside a docker container</title>
      <link>/posts/http-server-inside-a-docker-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/http-server-inside-a-docker-container/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article mainly focus on how to run a HTTP server inside a docer container. The key point is port mapping.
Basic setup I skipped installation of docker at ubuntu here. Please refer to my last docker note.
For server example, I have some in my github.
C version
Python flask
Rust version
Here I choose Rust version for example.
Run Rust docker # pull rust official image to local docker pull rust # run a container docker run -itd -p 8080:5000 --name httpserver rust Here -itd means &amp;lsquo;interactive&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;TTY&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;detached&amp;rsquo;, which are running options of container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run a basic gRPC example with Docker</title>
      <link>/posts/run-a-basic-grpc-example-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/run-a-basic-grpc-example-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The purpose of this article is very simple. Just run a gRPC example in different Docker containers. Since it really costed me a lot of time, I&amp;rsquo;d like to keep records here.
Docker is a very useful container tool, which can be considered as a light virtualization technique comparing to traditional virtual machine tools such as Virtualbox, VMware, etc. For more details about the differences between them, as well as the Docker&amp;rsquo;s basics, please refer this Stack Overflow question, the Digital Ocean tutorial, or the Docker official introduction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
